Guide to the Kasper Family Collection BCMS.0080
Brooklyn Collection
Kasper Family Collection
1945-1949
Brooklyn Collection
Hannan, Carol "Freddie" (Kasper), 1943-
BCMS.0080
0.2 Linear Feet in 1 box
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photographs and ephemera from the Kasper family of Brooklyn.
Biographical Note
The Kasper family lived at the Manhattan Beach Veterans Housing Project in South Brooklyn in the late 1940s. Irving Kasper had been discharged from the U.S. army in 1945. Carol Kasper (now Hannan), the donor, attended dance classes in Brighton Beach around 1948. She and her brother Marvin attended school at the Floyd Bennett Field Naval Center. They got to school, along with other neighborhood children, via a pony cart owned by a neighbor. She also recalled that her father's aunt, Jennie "Jean" Kasper, worked at the Brooklyn Navy Yard for 30 years, including as assistant to Rear Admiral Joseph Coghlan during WWII.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Carol "Freddie" Hannan, 2020.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in three series by type. The photographs are grouped as the donor had grouped them.
Related Materials
Fleck, H. Elizabeth. An evaluation of Manhattan Beach Veteran's Housing Project. New York, NY: 1947.
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.); Manhattan Beach (New York, N.Y.); Veterans -- New York (State) -- Kings County; Veterans; Dance recitals |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Children |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Hannan, Carol "Freddie" (Kasper), 1943-; Kasper, Marvin, 1941-; Kasper, Irving
- Family Photographs
  - Blizzard of 1947, 1947 December 26-27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Photographs depict Marvin and Carol Kasper playing in the 26.4" of snow that fell during the blizzard.
  - Manhattan Beach Veterans Housing Project, circa 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Other family photographs, circa 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Dance class photographs and programs
  Note
  Recitals were held in Manhattan but classes were in Brooklyn. The donor recalled going to Mrs. Stahl's Knishes at Brighton Beach and Coney Island Avenues after class for potato knishes.
  - Dance class photographs, circa 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dance class programs, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Irving Kasper ephemera
  - Maritime Beach admissions card, 1947 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographic print of group of WWII veterans (Box 1, Folder 6)
    General
    Irving Kasper is fourth from left in righthand grouping.
  - Army honorable discharge certificate, 1945 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 6)